<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drink on Flâneurist</title>
    <link>/tags/drink/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drink on Flâneurist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/drink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Dat Brass</title>
      <link>/post/all-about-dat-brass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/all-about-dat-brass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I emerged from the gymnasium into the cool night air. I had just completed another evening&amp;rsquo;s instruction in the Eastern martial arts, and was feeling invigorated, it being a weekly ritual before my soujourn from London Bridge to my rooms in Vauxhaul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having attained the pavement I became swept up along with the rest of the commutors flowing to or from the station. I was bound away from this hive of activity, towards my favourite part of town: the borough of Southwark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pronounced Suh-thuk, by the way, and damn and blast &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary#English_Dictionaries_in_Britain&#34;&gt;Samuel Johnson&lt;/a&gt; for codifying such nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned off Tooley Street and wandered past Borough Market, unbustled by the hurriers and worriers. There were yet many people here, it&amp;rsquo;s just that these people were stationary, with refreshments in hand, and therefore much easier to navigate around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the market itself, and indeed the whole of Southwark Street, closed tonight, but we Londoners are used to closed roads here and there - whole streets were dug up to install the Underground Railway after all - so we don&amp;rsquo;t bat an eye. Indeed, it was my great fortune that I diverted off my normal path (I must make a note to deviate more!), and on to Union Street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed many factory buildings and not a few pubs before I heard it: The sound of a band, but not just that: A band playing Herbie Hancock&amp;rsquo;s Chameleon - a personal favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sounds are not unusual on Union Street. Opposite the Rose And Crown (a Traditional pub with backpackers&amp;rsquo; hostel above, serving a mixture of British and Thai cuisine) is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lccm.org.uk/&#34;&gt;London College of Creative Media&lt;/a&gt;. Often when I pass there is the sound of all kinds of music (or, dear reader, what passes for such) issuing forth from the higher windows. This evening, however, though there was indeed some kind of function requireing a doorman happening within, the music that drew my attention was beyond. At the meeting of Union Street and Southwark Bridge Road there are railway arches. And within, a bar known as Flat Iron Square. And it was here I ducked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me set the scene, in the hemispherical venue were benches, a bar at one side, and in the centre of a throng: a modern brass band. They were led by an extrodinary Sousaphone bearing the band&amp;rsquo;s name: Dat Brass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/V6V3mwH.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Horn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gentlemen proceded to smash out some delightful covers of Mark Ronson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Valerie&lt;/em&gt;, My Lord Mix-a-Lot&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Baby Got Back&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Bad Touch&lt;/em&gt; by The Offspring, amoungst other expertly selected favourites. Sadly, I arrived at the end of their show, at just a hair before 9pm. I understand they had been their from 7pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/OYNHaql.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dancing on the tables&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was over all too soon, the band finished their final encore (many of which being much demmanded by the delighted audience), I finished my drink and slipped from my seat back out into the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much to my surprised, I found it raining upon my exit from the bar. It was the light sort of rain that only really bothers specticle-wearers, so I smiled and walked in the direction of the Borough Underground Railway station. On Marshalsea road, approaching the station, there is a large, imposing yellow-bricked building. This is one of Lord Peabody&amp;rsquo;s estates. A great philathropist, Peabody dispaired to see the state of the poor housing in the inner city, and built many buildings to try and give people warm, safe places for resonable rent. I understand it is the inspiration for the government&amp;rsquo;s social housing - and a jolly good thing. A city needs a few pockets of sanity in the housing market to keep the rest of the landlords anchored in reality!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/i2jpwb7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Peabody Trust. (c) Stephen Craven (CC BY-SA 2.0)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All too soon, as is the case with underground travel, I found myself back in my own neighborhood.
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a mixed blessing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought to myself as I walked the few well-trodden streets back to my rooms,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Underground gets one to one&amp;rsquo;s destination all right, and expediently, but it does nothing for the &lt;em&gt;journey&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>